These are the required content provider functions. You
can implement them any way you like, but
you'll find that it's really straight forward to
implement them on top of a SQLite database. The
parameters packed into our content provider functions match
the parameters used for Android's SQLite's interface almost
exactly. The biggest difference is that we replaced
the table string, with a uri. In the simplest
content provider implementation, the query is passed
straight through to the database. Note that
there are parameters that cannot be easily
controlled through content providers, such as grouping functionality.
But the interface allows for very flexible querying.
Most importantly, the projection or columns allows for querying
to be much more efficient. Because the column
indices and our cursor object match the projection that
we submit to the database, we can just
get the values by their numerical index instead of
having to use getColumnIndex to look up each
column index. All right, it's time to code some
more Sunshine. Let's code a content provider.